A Guide to Dr. Vamik D. Volkan Papers
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Correspondence from Harold H. Saunders with Saunders' Paper, "Thinking in Stages", 1992(2/26), TD (Box-folder 016:041)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Draft List of the Participants of the Seminar on the Problem of National Minorities in the Baltic Republics, 1992(4), TD (Box-folder 016:042)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Advisory Board Meeting and List of Accomplishments for 1991 and List of Goals for 1992, 1992(4/1), TD (Box-folder 016:043)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Determination Letters from IRS, 1992(7/7), TD (Box-folder 016:044)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Documentary Movie and Discussion, "Is It Easy To Be Young?" 1992(7/20), TD (Box-folder 016:045)
  Movie Invitation
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Academic Affiliation with IHSC (Institute for the Study of Human Conflict), 1992(7/31), TD (Box-folder 016:046)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Roundtable Meeting, 1992(8/5), TD (Box-folder 016:047)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Monograph on Racism, 1992(8/12), TD (Box-folder 016:048)
  Memorandum, Report
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Final Narrative Report: US-USSR Joint Study - Psychopolitical Approaches to Interethnic Conflict & Negotiation, 1992(9/15), TD (Box-folder 016:049)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Notes from Racism Meeting, 1992(9/20), TD (Box-folder 016:050)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Notes from Racism Meeting, 1992(9/22), TD (Box-folder 016:051)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Advisory Board Meeting Minutes, 1992(10/16), TD (Box-folder 016:052)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Grand Awards - "Ethnicity, Nationalism and Political Change - Baltic Project", 1993(2-3), TD (Box-folder 016:053)
  Report, Memorandum
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Report, "Shaking the Tent: The Psychodynamics of Ethnic Terrorism", 1993, Newsletter (Box-folder 016:054)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Monograph No. 2, "The Psychology of Western Europe Neo-Racism", 1993, TD (Box-folder 016:055)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Gorbachev's Wish for Founder's Birthday, "May Jeffersonian Ideals of Freedom Never Fade", 1993(3), TD (Box-folder 016:056)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Evaluation of the John Jay College and Suggested New Proposal, 1993(3/31), TD (Box-folder 016:057)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newsletter Center Pieces(Vol.1 No.1), 1993(4/1), newsletter (Box-folder 016:058)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: University of Virginia Founder's Day Address by Mikhail Sergeyevich Gorbachev, 1993(4/13), Photo, Pamphlet (Box-folder 016:059)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Six-Month Activity Report, 1993(5/7), TD (Box-folder 016:060)
  Reports, Letters, Memorandum, Newsletter Articles
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newsletter Center Pieces(Vol.1 No.2), 1993(7/1), Newsletter (Box-folder 016:061)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter from the Pew Charitable Trusts Grants Administrator, 1993(8/20), TD (Box-folder 016:062)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newsletter Center Pieces(Vol.1 No.3), 1993(10/1), Newsletter (Box-folder 016:063)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Advisory Board Meeting, 1993(11/19), TD (Box-folder 016:064)
  Report, Letters, Minutes
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter to Michale Sebek, 1993(12/9), TD (Box-folder 016:065)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Mind and Human Interation News(Volume 1, Number 4), 1994(Spring), Newsletter (Box-folder 016:066)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Interim Report on Kuwait Project, 1994(3/30), TD (Box-folder 016:067)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Ms. Katherine Clerides's Visit to Charlottesville, 1994(4-5), TD (Box-folder 016:068)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Kuwait Project [Literature Search] 1994(5/15), TD (Box-folder 016:069)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Up-To-Date Center Activities, 1994(1/11-12), TD (Box-folder 016:070)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Advisory Board Meeting Minutes, 1994(9/8), TD (Box-folder 016:071)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter to William E. Massey Jr., 1995(3/24), TD (Box-folder 016:072)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Advisory Board Meeting, 1995(4/24), TD (Box-folder 017:001)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Methology for Reduction of Ethinic Tension, and Promotion of Democratization and Institution Building, 1995(5), TD (Box-folder 017:002)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Project on Democratic Pluralism in Slovakia - Report on a Six Month Planning Grant and Resulting Proposal for the Project, 1995(5), TD (Box-folder 017:003)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: CSMHI: Project on Democratic Pluralism in Slovakia - Meeting with Jozef Sestak, 1995(5), TD (Box-folder 017:004)
  Meeting Report
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Project on Democratic Pluralism in Slovakia - Sharon L. Wolchik's Report, "The Development of Slovak Nationalism and its Contemporary Repercussions", 1995(5), TD (Box-folder 017:005)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Project on Democratic Pluralism in Slovakia - Janusz Bugajski's Trip Report, "Hungarian-Slovak Relations: the View From Budapest", 1995(5), TD (Box-folder 017:006)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Project on Democratic Pluralism in Slovakia [Volkan Visit to Slovakia], 1995(5), TD (Box-folder 017:007)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Project on Democratic Pluralism in Slovakia [Information of Bansk Stiavnica], 1995(5), TD (Box-folder 017:008)
  Photocopies of a book
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Project on Democratic Pluralism in Slovakia - Meeting of the CSIS Team with Lazslo Szigeti(4/26/1995), 1995(5), TD (Box-folder 017:009)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Project on Democratic Pluralism in Slovakia [Resume of Joseph V. Montville, 1995(5), TD (Box-folder 017:010)
  Resume
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Project on Democratic Pluralism in Slovakia [Resume of Dominik Bartosiewicz], 1995(5), TD (Box-folder 017:011)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Ethnic Reconciliation Demonstration Project in Estonia, 1995(9), TD (Box-folder 017:012)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newsletter Article, "The Diplomacy of Vamik Volkan", 1995(9), Newsletter (Box-folder 017:013)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: PASO Newsletter (Volume 4, Number 3), 1995(9), TD (Box-folder 017:014)
  NewsLetter
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter from Ambassador Tedo Japaridze, 1995(11/10), TD (Box-folder 017:015)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Symposium Announcement, "The First Annaul Symposium on Religious Fundamentalism and Cults in the United States and Abroad", 1995(9/17), Newspaper Clipping (Box-folder 017:016)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Lecture: Lessons in Culture, History and Medicine - "The Oklahoma City Federal Building Bombing, April 19 of 1995", 1995(9/20), TD (Box-folder 017:017)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter to B. Stephen Toben of the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation, 1995(9/25), TD (Box-folder 017:018)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Symposium on Religious Fundamentalism and Cults in the United States and Abroad, 1995(10/7), Pamphlet (Box-folder 017:019)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Lecture: Lee Harvey Oswald - "The Mind and Motive of JFK's Assassination", 1995(11/28), TD (Box-folder 017:020)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newspaper Article, "Project Completed, Ambassador Makes Journey Back to Kuwait", 1995(11/28), Newspaper Article (Box-folder 017:021)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newspaper Article, "UVa Faculty Work to Dissipate Environmental, Ethnic Poisons", 1995(11/29), TD (Box-folder 017:022)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: 1995, Newspaper Article (Box-folder 017:023)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Pamphlet, 1996, Pamphlet (Box-folder 017:024)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Lecture, "501 Days in Waco - A Psychological Profile of David Koresh", 1996(1/17), TD (Box-folder 017:025)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Publicity Guide of Advisory Board Meeting, 1996(1/22), TD (Box-folder 017:026)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Commission Report to the FBI's Critical Incident Response Group, 1996(2), TD (Box-folder 017:027)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newsletter Article on CSMHI, "Interdisciplinary Center Develops Model for Peace", 1996(Spring), Newsletter (Box-folder 017:028)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter from Robin Montgomery, 1996(3/11), Newsletter (Box-folder 017:029)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Narrative Report to the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation Year I, 1996(4), Report Book (Box-folder 017:030)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter from Institute of International and Social Studies of the Eastern Academy of Science, 1996(4/8), TD (Box-folder 017:031)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newspaper Article, "Mind and Human Interaction Center Receives $650,000 Grant", 1996(4/9), Newspaper Clipping (Box-folder 017:032)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newspaper Article, "UVa Conflict Resolution Center Awarded Grant", 1996(4/12), Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 017:033)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letters from Yuri Urbanovich, 1996(5/3), TD (Box-folder 017:034)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Memorandum to CSMHI Advisory Board Members, 1996(7/9), TD (Box-folder 017:035)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Joyce Neu's Presentation on "Coherence and Incoherence in Bosnian Reconstruction: Illusion of Peace", 1996(10/4), TD (Box-folder 017:036)
  Presentation Announcement
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Hendrik W. Van Der Merwe's Lecture, "Reflections on Conflict Resolution in South Africa", 1996(11/6), TD (Box-folder 017:037)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minutes, 1996(12/13), TD (Box-folder 017:038)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Report on the Blackwell Community Collaboration Team, 1997, TD (Box-folder 017:039)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Conferences and Presentations Teaching Publications, 1997, TD (Box-folder 017:040)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT - Instruments Developed by Collaboration Team, 1997, TD (Box-folder 017:041)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: PASO Newsletter (Volume 5, Number 3), 1997(1), Photocopies of Newsletter (Box-folder 017:042)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minutes, 1997(1/10), TD (Box-folder 017:043)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minutes, 1997(1/31), TD (Box-folder 017:044)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Richmond Project Proposal, 1997(3), TD (Box-folder 017:045)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Lecture and Discussion on "The State of Europe", 1997(3/17), TD (Box-folder 017:046)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Journal Article, "New Institute Instructs Kuwaits in Art of Diplomacy", 1997(3/28), Journal Article (Box-folder 017:047)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Narrative Report to the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation Year II, 1997(4), Report book (Box-folder 017:048)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Michael Rustin's Lecture, "The Good Society and the Inner World", 1997(5/6), TD (Box-folder 018:001)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minutes, 1997(6/13), TD (Box-folder 018:002)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newsletter Article About the Grant from the Massey Foundation, 1997(7), Newsletter (Box-folder 018:003)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letters from Estonian Parliament Members, 1997(7/5), TD (Box-folder 018:004)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting with Elaine Evans of Richmond Police Academy League, 1997(7/15), TD (Box-folder 018:005)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minutes, 1997(7/16), TD (Box-folder 018:006)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minutes, 1997(7/23), TD (Box-folder 018:007)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Blackwell Academy Program Overview 1997(8/25), TD (Box-folder 018:008)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minutes, 1997(9/24), TD (Box-folder 018:009)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Original Assessment of Proposal Evaluation of BCCT, 1997(9/25), TD (Box-folder 018:010)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Invitation to the Blackwell Saturday Academy Opening Program, 1997(9/27), Invitation Card (Box-folder 018:011)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Blackwell Saturday Academy Program Description and Progress Report, 1997(9/27)-1998(2/15), TD (Box-folder 018:012)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Blackwell Saturday Academy Program - Letters with Dr. John Ehrmantraut, 1997(9/29-10/7), TD, AD (Box-folder 018:013)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Letters, 1997(9/29-12/18), TD (Box-folder 018:014)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Evaluation Information and Handouts, 1997(9/30), TD, AD (Box-folder 018:015)
  Letters, Report, Evaluation Forms
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minutes, 1997(10/1), TD (Box-folder 018:016)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newspaper Article, "Film Documents UVa Center's Work in Resolving Age-Old Conflicts", /1997(10/3), Newspaper Article (Box-folder 018:017)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newspaper Article, Correspondence with Dr. Deborah Jones, 1997(10/7)-1998(1/2), TD (Box-folder 018:018)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Telephone Conversation Questions with the New York Times Magazine, 1997(10/16), TD (Box-folder 018:019)
  Letter, Questionaires
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minuite, 1997(10/22), TD (Box-folder 018:020)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: The Fifth Annual Stoller Memorial Lecture by Volkan, "Bloodlines: From Ethinc Pride to Terrorism", 1997(10/24), TD (Box-folder 018:021)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minutes, 1997(10/29), TD (Box-folder 018:022)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Proposal Report, "Child Survival Initiative - Civil Restoration in Angola: A Psychological issue", 1997(11), TD (Box-folder 018:023)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Position for Outreach Coordinator, 1997(11/6), TD (Box-folder 018:024)
  Application Form, Job Announcement
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newsletter Mind and Human Interaction (Volume 9, Number 3), 1998, Newsletter (Box-folder 018:025)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minutes, 1998(1/7), TD (Box-folder 018:026)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Conferences, Presentations, Project Meetings and Significant Activities, and Publications, 1998, TD (Box-folder 018:027)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: BCCT Meeting Minutes, 1998(2), TD (Box-folder 018:028)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Blackwell Saturday Academy Proposal Information Forms, 1998(2/4), TD (Box-folder 018:029)
  Proposal Forms
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Blackwell Saturday Academy Program Description and Progress Report, 1998(2/15), TD (Box-folder 018:030)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Journal Article about CSMHI, "A Psychoanalytically Based Program for Reducing International Conflicts", 1998(Spring), TD (Box-folder 018:031)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Advisory Board Meeting, 1998(2/11), TD (Box-folder 018:032)
  Reports, Newsletter Articles
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Narrative Report to the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation Year III, 1998(4), TD (Box-folder 018:033)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Preview Screening of the Documentary, "Suicide Bombers: Secrests of the Shaheed" and a Panel Discussion of Prospects for Peace in the Middle East, 1998(4/22), TD (Box-folder 018:034)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Report: "Psychoanalysis and Diplomacy Part I: Individual and Large Group Identity", 1998(7), TD (Box-folder 018:035)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Magazine Article, "A Therapy to Help Heal Society", 1998(Fall), TD (Box-folder 018:036)
  Letter, Magazine Article
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Case Statement, 1998(9), TD (Box-folder 018:037)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter from Karen B. Rendleman to Dr. Luis E. Lugo, 1998(9/18), TD (Box-folder 018:038)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Conferences, Presentations, Project Meetings, Activities and Publications, 1998(10), TD (Box-folder 018:039)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Panel Discussion, "Between Conflict and Reconciliation: Traumatized Society", 1998(10/13), Discussion Invitation Card (Box-folder 018:040)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Advisory Meeting, 1998(10/19), TD (Box-folder 018:041)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Report of Activities, 1998(11)-1999(11), TD (Box-folder 018:042)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter from J. Anderson Thomson Jr., 1998(1/29), TD (Box-folder 018:043)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter to David A. Hamburg, 1998(12/22), TD (Box-folder 018:044)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Report: "Ethno-Cultural Aspects of Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder and Sexual Trauma in Bosnian Refugees", 1998(12/22), TD (Box-folder 018:045)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Slide presentation of CSMHI in 1998 for Vice President Cantrell, 1999, TD (Box-folder 018:046)
  Photocopies of Slides
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Journal Article About CSMHI, "Analysis, International Relations, and History", 1999, TD (Box-folder 018:047)
  Journal
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter from Rebecca W. Rimel, 1999(2/5), TD (Box-folder 018:048)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Narrative Report to the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation Year III, 1999(42), TD (Box-folder 018:049)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Conference: "From Dialogue to Action: Models of Ethnic Reconciliation and Integration in Estonia", 1999(4/30-5/1), TD (Box-folder 019:001)
  Letters, Report, Conference Announcement
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter to the Pew Charitable Trusts, 1999(9/8-10/6), TD (Box-folder 019:002)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Final Report, "Reducing Transgenerational Transmission of Ethnic Conflict: A Model for the Republic of Georgia", 1999(10), TD (Box-folder 019:003)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter from David J. Morse of the Pew Charitable Trusts, 1999(10/21), TD (Box-folder 019:004)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Advisory Board Meeting, 1999(12/3), TD (Box-folder 019:005)
  Minutes, Photocopies of Slides
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Content of Mind and Human Interaction (Vol.10-11), 1999-2000, TD (Box-folder 019:006)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Notice of Award [Project Title: Helping the Helpers - Experimental Training], 2000(3/24), TD (Box-folder 019:007)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter to L. Marian Wouters, 2000(3/29), TD (Box-folder 019:008)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Narrative Report to the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation Year III, 2000(5), TD (Box-folder 019:009)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Reports of Some Recent Events, 2000(11/28), TD (Box-folder 019:010)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Advisory Board Meeting, 2000(5/24), TD, AD (Box-folder 019:011)
  Minutes, Report, Photocopies of Slides
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Memorandum on the Volkan Conference, 2000(5/25-6), TD (Box-folder 019:012)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: List of Speakers and Staff at the CSMHI Multidisciplinary Conference, "Identity, Mourning and Psycho-Political Process", 2000(5/25-6), TD (Box-folder 019:013)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: United States Institutes of Peace Special Report, "Training to Help Traumatized Populations", 2000(12/17), TD (Box-folder 019:014)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Final Report, "Gender Issues and Family Violence: Public Awareness and Services to Victims", 2000(7), TD (Box-folder 019:015)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI Newsletter: Mind and Human Interaction (Vol.13 No.1), 2003, Newsletter (Box-folder 019:016)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Profile for the Study of Mind and Human Interaction, 2003, TD (Box-folder 019:017)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newspaper Article, "Al Quida Auf Der Couch", 2004(6/14), TD (Box-folder 019:018)
  Newspaper Article
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: 150th Annniversary of Sigmund Freud, 2005(5/6), TD (Box-folder 019:019)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newspaper Article, "Suomen Kuvalehti", 2005(6/17), TD (Box-folder 019:020)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newspaper Article, "Professor Vamik D. Volkan: A Psychopolitical Approach to International Relations", 2005(6/8), TD (Box-folder 019:021)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter from the Sigmund Freud Foundation, 2005(12/4), TD (Box-folder 019:022)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: U.S. Scholars Orientation, 2006(2/27-8), TD (Box-folder 019:023)
  Participants List
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Newpaper Article, "Woraus Besteht Das Zelt?", 2006(6/16), TD (Box-folder 019:024)
  Newpaper Article
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Journal Article, "Putting Enemies on the Couch", 2007(2/28), TD (Box-folder 019:025)
  Journal Article
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter to Barry J. Collins and Allen Archer of UVa Medical Alumni Association / Medical School Foundation, 2007(5/4), TD (Box-folder 019:026)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Participants in the OECD World Forum on Statistics, Knowledge, and Policy, 2007(6/27-30), TD (Box-folder 019:027)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Correspondence with Carmen Feuchtner, 2007(12/12)-2008(1/31), TD (Box-folder 019:028)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter from John Akderdice, 2008(1/31), TD (Box-folder 019:029)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter to Dr. Davis Dean Brockman, 2008(2/2), TD (Box-folder 019:030)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Publication of "Statistics, Knowledge and Policy 2007: Measuring and Fostering the Progress of Societies", 2008(4/16), TD (Box-folder 019:031)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Letter from Virginius Pocius, N.D., TD (Box-folder 019:032)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Invitation to Russell H. Davis's Lecture on "Freud and the Concept of Passivity", N.D., TD (Box-folder 019:033)
  Lecture Invitation
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Invitation to Judith F. Chused's Lecture on "The Patient's Reception of the Analyst", N.D., TD (Box-folder 019:034)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Meeting with Interviewers, N.D., TD (Box-folder 019:035)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Invitation to Joseph Lichtenberg's Lecture on "Motivational Systems Approach to the Clinical Encounter", N.D., TD (Box-folder 019:036)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Website Information of CSMHI, N.D., Brochure, Report, Photocopies of the CSMHI Website (Box-folder 019:037)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - CSMHI: Slides, N.D., 199 Slides (Box-folder 020:001)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Chautauqua Project: Volkan's Participation in Chautauqua Program During International Affairs Week, 1985(1/30-2/4), TD (Box-folder 020:002)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Chautauqua Project: Article on Vamik Volkan in [The Chautauquan Daily], 1985(6/11), TD (Box-folder 020:003)
  Letter, Newspaper Article
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Chautauqua Project: Chautauqua Conference on US-Soviet Relaions, 1985(6/24-8), TD, Newspaper Clipping (Box-folder 020:004)
  letters, Conference Program
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Chautauqua Project: Invitation of Russian Poet Andrei Voznesensky, 1985(7/5), TD (Box-folder 020:005)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Chautauqua Project: Correspondence After the Chautauqua Conference, 1985(7/5), TD (Box-folder 020:006)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Arab-Israel Project: Letters from Bennett Simon and Roberta J. Apfel About the Plan for the 'Children-in-War' Conference, 1989(7/5-14), TD (Box-folder 020:007)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Arab-Israel Project: List of Participants and Titles of Talks at the 'Children-in-War' Conference, 1995, TD (Box-folder 020:008)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Arab-Israel Project: Photocopies of Children's Drawings at the 'Children-in-War' Conference, 1995, Photocopies of Drawings (Box-folder 020:009)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Arab-Israel Project: Volkan's Letter to Bennett Simon and Roberta J. Apfel Concerning the Follow-ups of the 'Children-in-War' Conference, 1995, TD (Box-folder 020:010)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Arab-Israel Project: Report on the APA American-Israeli-Egyptian-Palestian Meetings Held 1980-1986, "Should They Be Reactivated?" 1995, TD (Box-folder 020:011)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Arab-Israel Project: Second Joint Statement of the Israeli-Palestinian Committee, "An Urgent Second Message to the Israeli and Palestian Leadership", 1995, TD (Box-folder 020:012)
- Vamik Volkan Tapes: The Dragon's Egg 1999, Video Tapes(1) (Box-folder 020:013)
  The movie explores ethnic reconciliation by seeing what happens when a group of American scholars led by Volkan offers $50,000 to any group of Estonians and Russians living in Estonia to work together for a common goal.